<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Tyranny of Dragons</title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://npf.io/tod/adventure-log/index.xml/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Nate Finch</author>
    <copyright>2014 Nate Finch</copyright>
    <updated>Sat, 06 Sep 2014 06:53:23 EDT</updated>
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Session 1 - Greenest in Flames</title>
      <link>http://npf.io/tod/adventure-log/2014/09/06/session1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2014 06:53:23 EDT</pubDate>
      <author>Nate Finch</author>
      <guid>http://npf.io/tod/adventure-log/2014/09/06/session1/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Pregame&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had seven players for the first session - Jeff, Matt, SteveF, SteveL, ChrisB,
ChrisY, and Rose.  All are college buddies of mine except for Rose, who is
ChrisB&amp;rsquo;s wife.  Most had made up their characters beforehand, and we rolled for
ability scores when they arrived.  Jeff stayed true to his legend and started us
out with a ridiculous set of scores, only one of which was below 14, and that
one was merely a 10.  Given that Jeff&amp;rsquo;s dice had done so well for him, everyone
else wisely decided to use his dice when rolling.  The great rolls continued,
and only petered out when they finally trickled down to Rose and SteveL, both of
whom took the option of the standard array when the dice failed to produce
better stats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The party breakdown looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Player&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Race/Class&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Nate&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;DM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;DM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Matt&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Human Druid&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Rose&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Wood-elf Ranger&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Jeff&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Human Fighter&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://npf.io/tod/pcs/krogan/&#34;&gt;Krogan, son of Djorn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;SteveF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Halfling Rogue&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://npf.io/tod/pcs/welby/&#34;&gt;Welby Greenbottle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;SteveL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Half-Orc Barbarian&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://npf.io/tod/pcs/grogh/&#34;&gt;Grogh the Barbarian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;ChrisB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Human Wizard&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://npf.io/tod/pcs/bortels/&#34;&gt;ER Bortels&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;ChrisY&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Human Fighter&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes&amp;hellip; even with 7 players, no one wanted to be the cleric.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;The Adventure&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the adventure starts, the party is guarding a caravan of silk bolts destined
for merchants in &lt;a href=&#34;http://npf.io/tod/locations/greenest/&#34;&gt;Greenest&lt;/a&gt;.  Upon cresting a hill overlooking the
town, the party sees it beseiged by a dragon and overrun with cultists and
kobolts. The players hotly debate the merits of charging into a town being
attacked by a dragon.  An ambush by kobolds is drawn by the sounds of their
bickering, and their surprise round attacks deal some mighty blows to party,
before being summarily dispatched by a well-placed sleep spell from the wizard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This evidently sways &lt;a href=&#34;http://npf.io/tod/pcs/bortels/&#34;&gt;ER Bortels&lt;/a&gt; enough to have the caravan move towards
town rather than heroically run away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon entering the outskirts of town, four humans run out from between buildings
- an injured man carrying a baby and half-dragging a young child following by a
woman carrying a shield and a spear.  The woman stops midway across the road and
turns resolutely to face the four kobolds and two cultists that emerge from
between the buildings behind them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With somewhat less bickering this time, the party closes in to help the woman,
and easily dispatches the enemy combatants.  The woman introduces herself as &lt;a href=&#34;http://npf.io/tod/npcs/linan/&#34;&gt;Linan Swift&lt;/a&gt;, a commoner, and her husband is Cuth. They tell the party of the
beginning of the raid of the town less than an hour ago, and their belief that
the only safe place in town is the keep.  With this advice, the party decides to
move towards the keep, though they are hampered by the two wagons in the
caravan. Finding an already-looted stone barn slightly down the road, they stash
the wagon with the valuable merchant goods, and continue on toward the keep with
only &lt;a href=&#34;http://npf.io/tod/pcs/bortels/&#34;&gt;ER Bortels&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s personal wagon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This procession of a wagon and 11 people in and around it draws a lot of
attention, and both raiders and common folk flock to it with equal abandon,
though with disparate purposes.  Upon reaching the keep, the party is ushered
inside just as the great doors are closed for the last time, with hoards of
raiders coming to surround the keep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The party is only slightly hurt at this point, but it is becoming more clear
that the lack of healing the party is likely to be a hindrance now that short
rests are 1 hour long.  With a timely suggestion from the DM, healer&amp;rsquo;s kits and
the associated feat to allow them to heal hitpoints are looked up. It is
determined that Matt&amp;rsquo;s human druid has not actually taken a first level feat,
and so with tears in his eyes, he lowers 4 of his ability scores by 1 and
acquires the Healer feat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon entering the keep, the commoners who were saved by the party tell the
guards of their saviors, and the guards usher the party up into the keep to meet
with &lt;a href=&#34;http://npf.io/tod/npcs/nighthill/&#34;&gt;Governor Tarbaw Nighthill&lt;/a&gt;.  Governor Nighthill is in rough shape, evidently
haven taken quite a few wounds fighting with the raiders and not wasting any
time on bandaging himself.  He tells the party of the raid which started only an
hour before, and that the town could really use the help of the adventurers in
rescuing some of the townsfolk trapped outside the keep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just then, &lt;a href=&#34;http://npf.io/tod/npcs/escobert/&#34;&gt;Castellan Escobert the Red&lt;/a&gt; comes into the room and tells Governor Nighthill
of a large number of people trapped in a temple in town, surrounded by raiders.
Nighthill turns to the party and asks if they would be able to help.  Escobert
suggests the party use an old tunnel under the keep to avoid the hoard of
raiders outside the gates. The party agrees that this is probably better than
trying to fight their way out, and enters the tunnel, only to be attacked by two
swarms of rats.  The rats are quickly dispatched, and the party makes it to the
exit of the tunnel.  A group of raiders passing the tunnel exit is ambushed and
dispatched quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon reaching the temple, the party sees a very large band of raiders slowly
circling the temple, and a less large, but still formidable group of raiders
attacking the front doors of the temple with a battering ram.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://npf.io/tod/pcs/welby/&#34;&gt;Welby Greenbottle&lt;/a&gt;
remembers there is a back door to the temple, but rather than investigate an
easier entrance, and risk the door collapsing before they make up their minds,
the party attacks the large force at the front door head-on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mighty &lt;a href=&#34;http://npf.io/tod/pcs/grogh/&#34;&gt;Grogh the Barbarian&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://npf.io/tod/pcs/krogan/&#34;&gt;Krogan, son of Djorn&lt;/a&gt; lead the charge, with the
ranged attackers staying slightly behind them.  Grogh flies into a rage, and
slays some of his foes, but the two dragonclaw cultists in the group bring their
formidable attacks to bear on him, doing heavy damage even with the barbarian&amp;rsquo;s
rage causing him to ignore half the damage being done.  Krogan steps into the
fray to help, relying on his high AC and heavy armor specialization to keep him
alive, but the party can&amp;rsquo;t bring down the dragonclaws before they bring down
Grogh.  SteveL, Grogh&amp;rsquo;s player, rolled two death saving throws, a success and a
failure, before rolling a 1, and causing Grogh to go be no more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The party finishes up most of the rest of the enemy group before the last few
flee for their lives, and slip around the side of the temple, out of bow and
firebolt range.  The party assumes (correctly) that those enemies will bring
back the large horde circling the temple, and so hurry to evacuate the people
from the building&amp;hellip;. with one small problem.  They&amp;rsquo;re still on the outside of
the building, and the people inside don&amp;rsquo;t know who they are.  The silver tongued
halfling tries in vain to convince the terrified people inside that the people
who are now talking through the door are not bent on their destruction, but to
no avail.  Then, Krogan, with his amazing stats steps up and gives it a try, and
even with disadvantage manages to convince the people in the temple to open the
door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The party quickly evacuates the temple and manages to get all the survivors back
into the tunnel under the keep without any problems (mostly due to the DM&amp;rsquo;s time
constraints on the session).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And thus ends the first session of Tyranny of Dragons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;Afterword&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it is great that the party rescued the people in the temple, it is sad
that Grogh had to give his life to do so.  In retrospect, maybe the players
should have taken the DM&amp;rsquo;s suggestion to investigate the back door.  The players
make a joke that maybe SteveL should make a cleric for the party and have him be
in the group of people that were saved from the temple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much is made of how powerful those dragonclaw cultists were for a first level
adventure&amp;hellip; but one must remember, just because there are enemies, does not
mean you must attack them.  There are often other ways.  Like back doors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the night, the DM declares that anyone who would like to change
what class they have chosen may do so, just this once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;Group XP Awards&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Enemy&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;XP&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;17 NPCs brought to keep&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;425&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;32 Kobolds Killed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;1600&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9 Cultists&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;225&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2 Dragonclaws&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;300*&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Temple Rescue&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;700&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2 Rat Swarms&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;100&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;= 478xp per character&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Slightly reduced from listed XP due to the DM forgetting they actually have two
attacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_4&#34;&gt;Individual Awards&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Player&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Bonus/Penalty&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;XP&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ChrisY&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;ldquo;Let&amp;rsquo;s just wait for the dragon to leave&amp;rdquo; penalty.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;-0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ChrisB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;ldquo;Let&amp;rsquo;s actually participate in the adventure&amp;rdquo; bonus.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;+5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Matt&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&amp;ldquo;Insert a quarter for healing&amp;rdquo; penalty.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;-0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Matt&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Taking one for the team with no cleric bonus.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;+10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jeff&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Weighted dice penalty.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;-0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SteveL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ballsy bearded barbarian bonus.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;+5*&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SteveF&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1000 ball bearings bonus.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;+0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rose&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Newbie bonus&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;+5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*applies to new character&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Beginning</title>
      <link>http://npf.io/tod/adventure-log/2014/09/06/beginning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2014 06:52:34 EDT</pubDate>
      <author>Nate Finch</author>
      <guid>http://npf.io/tod/adventure-log/2014/09/06/beginning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the website for my D&amp;amp;D campaign, running through the Tyranny of Dragons,
by Wizards of the Coast.  This is mainly for use of the players to keep track of
what has happened and what is going on in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>